A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry FA582
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry
1952-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA582
10.8 Cubic Feet
Wilson McNeil Lowry joined the Ford Foundation in 1953 as Program Director of Education. Mr. Lowry helped develop the Foundation's nascent program in the Humanities and the Arts and served as its first Director when the program was formally established in 1957. He later went on to serve as Vice President of the Office of Policy and Planning (1964-1966), Vice President of the Division of Humanities and the Arts (1965-1975), and Acting President of the Foundation (1965- 1966). He retired in 1975. The Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry document his oversight of numerous Ford Foundation programs, including Administration (ADMIN), Education (ED), Economic Development Administration (EDA), Fund for Adult Education (FAE), Humanities and the Arts (HA), International Affairs (IA), International Training and Research (ITR), Overseas Development (OD), Public Affairs (PA), Policy and Planning (P&P), Population (POP), Science and Engineering (SE), and Special Projects (SPE). These Program Files make up the bulk of the collection. There are also files on the activities of the Board of Trustees as well as on the planning of the new Ford Foundation building in New York, the Building Committee, and the dedication ceremony in 1967. The files also include documents prepared or assembled by his staff, for example, on the Travel Study Award Program, and records of site visits to Arts and Humanities Program grantees and potential grantees. Of particular note in the collection are the extensive records of the Ford Foundation's involvement with and financial support for the McCone Commission investigation of the 1965 Los Angeles Watts Riots.
(27 Hollinger document boxes)
Biographical/Historical note
Wilson McNeil Lowry (1913-1993) was born on February 17, 1913 in Columbus, Kansas. He graduated from the University of Illinois with a B.A. in 1934 and taught in the University’s Department of English from 1936 to 1941 when he received a PhD in English from the University. After service as a Navy lieutenant in World War II, Mr. Lowry worked in journalism, first as Associate Editor of the Dayton Daily News (1946-1947), then Chief of the Washington Bureau of James M. Cox Newspapers (1947-1952). He was Associate Director of the International Press Institute (1952-1953) when he was hired by the Ford Foundation as an assistant to William McPeak in order to direct the Foundation’s education program. Mr. Lowry helped develop the Foundation’s program in the area of Humanities and the Arts, and served as its first director when the program was formally established in 1957. He later served as Vice President of the Office of Policy and Planning (1964-1966), Vice President of the Division of Humanities and the Arts (1965-1975) and Acting President of the Foundation for a short time after the retirement of Henry T. Heald, until McGeorge Bundy was hired (1965-1966). Mr. Lowry retired in 1975, but continued to work as a pro bono consultant in the arts, including a term as president of the San Francisco Ballet (1988-1991). He died on June 6, 1993.
Biographical/Historical note
The Office of the Arts originated as the Office of Humanities and the Arts, created in 1957 under the direction of its first Vice President, Wilson McNeil Lowry. In 1979, the Office of the Arts became a program area under Education and Public Policy, and after the 1997 reorganization, became part of Education, Media, Arts and Culture. Education, Media, Arts and Culture became the Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program in 2002.
Arrangement
Arranged into 5 series.
Scope and Contents note
The Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry document his participation in and oversight of several Ford Foundation programs and departments. Mr. Lowry also served on the Board of Trustees and his files consist of the policies and procedures developed for and used by the Ford Foundation following the re-establishment of the Foundation in New York City. The files also include documents prepared or assembled by Mr. Lowry’s staff, e.g., on the Travel Study Award Program. There are also records of visits to grantees and potential grantees in the field of Arts and Humanities. Of particular note are the extensive records of the Ford Foundation’s involvement with and financial support for the McCone Commission investigation of the 1965 Los Angeles Watts Riots.
Separated Materials note
Four dictation disks on the University of Wisconsin Urban Extension Program, dated 1/2/1963 and six reel-to-reel audio recordings of Mr. Lowry’s speech at the Studio Arena Theatre Conference, 1967, have been separated and stored in Box 47480. A partial transcription of Mr. Lowry speaking at the Buffalo Studio Area Theatre Conference on 4/21/1967 has been tentatively associated with the reel-to-reel audio tapes and is available in Series V. Speeches and Writings of this collection.
Separated Materials note
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Related Archival Materials note
The University Archives of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign holds the W. McNeil Lowry Papers, 1941-1993, among their Alumni records. A more complete description of the collection and access requirements may be found online at the University Archives website.
Ford Foundation
- Board of Trustees, Bulk, 1966 1954-1972; bulk; I
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The files primarily are composed of docket files for Board of Trustees meetings and contain grant proposals and memoranda concerning the viability of the proposals. There are also a few discussion papers about subjects brought before the board, such as the College Investment Trust (1954-1967), and related correspondence.
  - College Investment Trust, May 26, 1954 - Jan 6, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Approved Budgets, 1957 - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Foundation Finances, Staff, Grants and Grantmaking Policies, etc., 1958 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda Re: Board Meeting Discussion Items, Nov 11, 1959 - Feb 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Henry Ford Hospital Proposal, May 22, 1961 - Mar 27, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grants to Harvard University -- Proposal Initiated Through John J. McCloy, Jul 26, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sabbaticals for High School Teachers -- Proposal Initiated Through John J. McCloy, Jul 27, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda Relating To or Initiated Through Board Members, Jan 11, 1963 - Jan 7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Warren Weaver Correspondence Re: Salk Institute for Biological Studies Proposal, Sep 16, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Warren Weaver Correspondence Re: Book on Philanthropy, Mar 9, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charles E. Wyzanski Jr. Correspondence Re: Medical School Proposal, Feb 6 - 14, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bethuel M. Webster's Trip to England, Denmark and Finland, Aug 4 - Sep 10, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Henry T. Heald Retirement, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Education, Feb 2 - Mar 30, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Economic Development Administration, Feb 1 - Feb 15, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- General, Jan 5 - Feb 11, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Humanities and the Arts, Feb 2 - Feb 9, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- International Affairs, Dec 31, 1965 - Feb 9, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- International Training and Research, Jan 19 - Feb 8, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Public Affairs, Jan 26 - Feb 17, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Population, Feb 4, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Science and Engineering, Jan 20 - Feb 10, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Docket, March 1966 -- Special Programs, Jan 26 - Feb 9, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Education, May 5 - 27, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Economic Development Administration, May 12, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- General, Apr 15 - May 20, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Humanities and the Arts, May 18, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- International Affairs, Apr 11 - May 20, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- International Training and Research, May 9 - 19, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Public Affairs (1 of 2), May 13 - Jun 1, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Public Affairs (2 of 2), May 12, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Population, May 12, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Science and Engineering, May 20, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Docket, June 1966 -- Special Programs, May 17, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Education, May 19 - Aug 24, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- General, Aug 15, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Humanities and the Arts, Aug 11 - 25, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- International Affairs, Jul 11 - Aug 12, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Overseas Development, Aug 8 - 25, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Population, Aug 11, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Science and Engineering, Aug 22, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Docket, September 1966 -- Special Programs, Jul 20 - 26, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Education, Oct 31, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Economic Development Administration, Nov 1, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- International Affairs, Oct 12 - 31, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- International Training and Research, Nov 7, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- National Affairs/Resources and the Environment, Oct 31, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Overseas Development, Nov 1, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Population, Oct 28, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Public Affairs, Aug 26 - Nov 11, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Docket, December 1966 -- Special Programs, Oct 31, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Forecasting and Financial Policy of the Ford Foundation, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Memoranda, May 25, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Possible New Trustees -- Memorandum, Biographies, May 25 - 26, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Travel and Study Award Program, Jan 27, 1967 - Jul 23, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Individual Award Programs: A Brief Survey", Jan 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Dependent Organizations" -- Paper/List of Organizations Receiving Foundation Support, Dec 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dependent Organizations -- Memoranda, Notes, Paper Draft, Jul 30 - Sep 3, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Ford Foundation and "Dependent" Organizations, Sep 16, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Humanities and the Arts (HA) Discussion Papers, May 24 - Jun 2, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Building-Related Files, 1963-1968; II
  These three files contain information on the Ford Foundation building, the Building Committee, and the dedication ceremony in 1967. Included is planning information about the Foundation’s move into the building and floor plans detailing where each department was relocating. The specific offices into which Foundation executives such as Mr. Lowry moved are also identified.
  - 320 East 43rd Street -- Memoranda, Articles, Press Clippings Re: Move to and Uses of New Building, Apr 12, 1967 - Jul 23, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Building Committee, Jun 18, 1963 - Aug 7, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation Building Dedication -- Memorandum, Invitations, Programs, Dec 1, 1967 - Mar 28, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Grant-Related Files, 1959-1966; III
  The files consist of a few grant requests with accompanying memoranda for the Education, Humanities and the Arts, Overseas Development, Population and Public Affairs programs.
  - Education -- The Fund For the Advancement of Education, Feb 25, 1963 - Jun 23, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Grants-in-Aid Programs, Oct 29, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Grant Requests, May 14, 1963 - May 20, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Independent Art Schools, Jun 14, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Program for Orchestras, Feb 11 - Jun 3, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Overseas Development -- Grant Requests and Discussion Memoranda, Mar 22, 1963 - Sep 1, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Overseas Development -- Middle East and Africa (MEA) Grant Requests, Dec 26, 1962 - Jul 22, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Overseas Development -- South and Southeast Asia (S & SEA) Grant Requests, Dec 27, 1962 - Jul 22, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Population - Grant Requests and Grant Summaries, May 13, 1964 - May 6, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Public Affairs - Grant Requests, 1959 - 1966 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Programs, 1952-1971; IV
  The files have been arranged alphabetically by program area and then by chronological order.
  Correspondence, memoranda, evaluations and reports from specific program areas have been arranged by program area: Administration (ADMIN), Education (ED), Economic Development Administration (EDA), Fund for Adult Education (FAE), Humanities and the Arts (HA), International Affairs (IA), International Training and Research (ITR), Overseas Development (OD), Public Affairs (PA), Policy and Planning (P&P), Population (POP), Science and Engineering (SE), and Special Projects (SPE). Staff memoranda, reports, and correspondence that concern more than one program area or cannot be clearly identified as having originated from a specific program have been filed before the clearly identified program materials.
  The largest sets of files are for Education and Policy and Planning, indicative of Mr. Lowry’s several years of oversight. Of particular note are the extensive Policy and Planning files concerning the issue of “Negro education” and the Foundation’s Urban Extension Programs at various universities. The Public Affairs files reveal the Foundation’s support for the investigation of the 1965 Watts riots in Los Angeles. The Science and Engineering folder on Conservation (1962-1965) represents the Foundation’s work in conservation and the environment, which would become a new program area in 1966, and includes a federal task force report entitled "The Preservation of Natural Beauty" (1964). One member of that task force was William H. Whyte.
  - Canada, Oct 11 - Nov 5, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe (2/24-25/1971) -- "Implications of Certain European-Based Activities and Interests for Ford Foundation Objectives in Asia and the Pacific", Feb 24 - 25, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe (2/24-25/1971) -- "Memorandum on the Foundation's Interest and Work in Education and Research in Europe," "Public Education Program Interests," and "Activities of Higher Education" (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe (2/24-25/1971) -- "Middle East and Africa (MEA) Interest in Europe" (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe (2/24-25/1971) -- "National Affairs' International Activities" (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe (2/24-25/1971) -- "Notes on Latin American Interest and Activity in Europe" (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Ford Foundation Grants and Projects in the Study of Philanthropy", Apr 15, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Individual Grants and Tax Consequences, Aug 11, 1969 - Apr 24, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - International Affairs (IA) Cultural Grants Transferred to Division of Humanities and Arts, Oct 4, 1966 - Jan 4, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Jesuit Padre Harbrecht to Heald Re: "New Foundations", Oct - Nov 9, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Population Grants in Europe, Feb 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Research Project on Attitudes Toward the Foundation and Ford Cars and Public Opinion Poll, Dec 3, 1963 - Jul 27, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Federal Tax Exemption Rules, Oct 26, 1960 - Oct 10, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Instructions for Grant Preparation, Nov 11, 1958 - Nov 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Miscellaneous, 1962 - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Overseas Grants Tax Exemptions, Oct 24 - Dec 22, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Travel Arrangements, Mar 24, 1960 - May 14, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Staff Memoranda -- Staff Appointments, Apr 4, 1963 - Sep 25, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Statistical Report on Program Action Disposition, Sep 26 - Oct 1, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Admin -- Administration Plans for 1966, Apr 16 - May 3, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Education -- Educational Facilities Lab, Jan 22 - Aug 6, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Education -- General, Feb 4, 1965 - Jun 13, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Education -- Vocational Education -- General, Apr 23 - Oct 31, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Education -- Report on Vocational Education as a Field for Ford Foundation Activity, Sep 4, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Evaluations -- General, Feb 16, 1959 - Aug 17, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Evaluation of the Joint Council on Economic Education, May 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Evaluation of the Economics Institute, Jul 31, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Evaluation of Fellowship Programs in Business Administration and Economics, Feb 15, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Grant Requests, Feb 15, 1963 - Aug 24, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Economic Development Administration -- General, Nov 18, 1964 - Jul 7, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Economic Development Administration -- Policy Discussion Paper, Jan 15, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE), Apr 1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Humanities and the Arts (HA) -- Educational Television, Nov 17, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - HA -- Social Position of Artist and His Institutions, Apr 8, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - HA -- Inquiry into the Support of Arts in France, UK, Denmark and Italy, Jul 2 - Aug 11, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - HA -- "An Enlarged Program in the Arts", Mar 1960 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - HA -- Edward F. D'Arms, Warsaw Trip, Polish Team (1 of 2), Jan 5 - Feb 13, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - HA -- Edward F. D'Arms, Warsaw Trip, Polish Team (2 of 2), 1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - HA -- Edward F. D'Arms Staff Trip to Yugoslavia, Feb 1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - HA -- "The Arts and The Ford Foundation: 1969", Dec 1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - HA -- General, Dec 5, 1962 - Aug 19, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - HA -- Neiman Fellows, Harvard, Dec 18, 1964 - Feb 21, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - HA -- India/Asia, Oct 17, 1967 - Feb 12, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - HA -- New York Planning Commission, Nov 30, 1967 - Feb 8, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - HA -- European Activities, Dec 29, 1967 - Mar 21, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - HA -- "Government Policy in the Arts", Aug 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - HA -- "Ford Foundation Strategy in the Arts - A Review", Nov 19, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - HA -- European Luncheon Club, Sep 17, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - HA -- Subcommittee Meeting, Board Meeting, Dec 16, 1969 - Mar 5, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - HA -- Grant Requests (1 of 3), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - HA -- Grant Requests (2 of 3), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - HA -- Grant Requests (3 of 3), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - International Affairs (IA) -- Humanities and the Arts (HA) Relations, Jan 29, 1957 - Feb 24, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - IA -- "An Independent Report on the Graduate School of Public Administration at the University of Bologna" by James Watson & Guglielmo Negri, Mar 1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - IA -- Institute for Research and Publications Madrid Meeting, Mar 15 - Jun 25, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - IA -- Svimez Evaluation, Apr 13, 1962 - Dec 9, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - IA -- "Report to the Ford Foundation International Affairs Program on the Free University Berlin and the West German Universities" by Sigmund Neumann, Jul 17, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - IA -- Evaluation -- General, Aug 21, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - IA -- Grant Request Items, Oct 8, 1962 - Aug 16, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - IA -- "Foreign Affairs and Mass Media: (U.S. Public Understanding of World Affairs)" by Theodore Kaghan, Jan 4, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - IA -- Report on Graduate Institute of International Studies at Geneva by Philip E. Mosely, Feb 1, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - IA -- "Strengthening the Comprehensive Development of the Atlantic Partnership", Mar 1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - IA -- "Strengthening the Comprehensive Development of the Atlantic Partnership" Discussion Paper, Mar 18, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - IA -- General, Mar 22, 1963 - Sep 14, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - IA -- Citizen's Education in World Affairs (1 of 2), Jan 28, 1964 - Dec 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - IA -- Citizen's Education in World Affairs (2 of 2), Sep 28 - Dec 22, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - IA -- Citizen's Education in World Affairs -- Robert Tucker's Notes, Dec 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - IA -- "International Affairs Discussion Paper: Review of International Affairs-Supported Conferences and Meetings", May 27, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - IA -- "Report on Committee on Citizen Education in World Affairs", Feb 15, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - IA -- United Nations Association -- Memoranda, Dec 16, 1965 - Jan 17, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - IA -- Rapprochement -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Jun 18 - Sep 2, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - International Development -- Soviet and East European Fellowship Program -- Memoranda, Reports, Mar 19 - Jun 21, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - International Training and Research (ITR) -- South Africa Leader Exchange Program, Sep 12, 1960 - Jun 17, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - ITR -- Material Sent to International Legal Studies Program Consultants, 1961 - Jan 19, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ITR -- International Legal Studies (1 of 2), 1962 - May 31, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)